What is the capital of France?
If you are curious about the capital of France,
you might be surprised to learn that it has not always been Paris.
Paris is the current and most populous capital of France,
with more than 2 million residents in an area of 105 square kilometers.
It is also one of the world's major centers of culture,
fashion, and gastronomy, and it is known as the City of Light for its role in the
Enlightenment and its early street lighting system.
But Paris was not always the seat of power in France.
In fact, throughout history, the capital has changed several times,
depending on the political and religious circumstances of the time.
Some of the other cities that have served as the capital of France include
Reims, the city where most of the French kings were crowned.
Reims was the capital during the Merovingian dynasty,
5th–8th centuries, and again during World War I,
when Paris was threatened by German invasion.
Aachen. The city where Charlemagne, the first